

## Normandy Park, WA 98166

**Phone:** 253-653-7120

Email: josh@joshtaylordesign.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/josh-taylor-738bb218/

**GitHub:** https://github.com/JoshTDesign **Portfolio:** https://jtdesign.herokuapp.com/

## **SUMMARY**

A CREATIVE UX/UI DESIGNER AND DEVELOPER with deep experience in branding and design. Self-directed and comfortable in every stage of project development, and able to deliver effective, user-first experiences. After earning a certificate in full-stack web development from the University of Washington, well-positioned to leverage latest technologies with timeless principles of branding and design.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Javascript, HTML, CSS, MySQL

**Applications:** Github, Figma, Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, AdobeXD, Blender3D **Frameworks:** TailwindCSS, Express.js, Node.js, UIKit, Materialize, ReactJS, Sequelize

## WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

#### CIRCLE COMMUNITY BULLETIN

https://github.com/JoshTDesign/Circle-Community-Bulletin | http://oui-circle-app.herokuapp.com/ A social bulletin board that connects community members with one another using geodata to organize and display postings by proximity.

Role: project manager, front-end design lead.

**Technology:** TailwindCSS, Express.js, Sequelize, mySQL, Node.js, Cloudinary, geoIP, bcrypt

## **PAW PAIR**

https://github.com/JoshTDesign/Paw-Pair | https://joshtdesign.github.io/Paw-Pair/ Paw Pair is a simple, fun tool for getting matched with your perfect pet companion.

Role: project manager, front-end design lead.

Technology: UI Kit, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Petfinder API

#### **RALLY TRAVEL APP**

https://github.com/JoshTDesign/project-3 | https://rally-travel.herokuapp.com/

Rally is an app to help you and your friends travel with ease. Track budgets, explore activities, plan an itinerary and more.

Role: front-end design lead, github manager.

**Technology:** Materialize, ReactJS, Express.js, Cloudinary, geoIP, bcrypt, mySQL, Sequelize

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## DESIGNER (OWNER) JOSH TAYLOR DESIGN

2013 - PRESENT SEATTLE, WA

Worked with companies large and small as an independent designer to bring complicated projects to life. Responsible for generating new logos, concepts, and assets for a variety of products and industries.

## **Key Accomplishments:**

- Conceptualized restaurant brands for Holland America Line. Created logos, dining room signage, menus, products and advertising layouts.
- Collaborated with a team of designers to refresh the Holland America Line brand and implement new logos and standards.
- Developed environmental sign packages and guidelines for Holland America Line. Regularly met with stakeholders and signage manufacturers to implement signage on new ships.
- Produced digital stage graphics for AJC's Annual Global Forum.

## MANAGER, ONBOARD MEDIA HOLLAND AMERICA LINE

2011 – 2013 SEATTLE, WA

Managed all digital and printed media on board fifteen Holland America Line ships. This position required juggling complicated projects under tight deadlines with multiple stakeholders and translating abstract goals into real-world products. Attention to detail and brand consistency were key to success in this position.

## **Key Accomplishments:**

- Oversaw signage, print communication, and digital experience on board.
- Travelled to new-build and drydock locations to watch over signage installations.
- Implemented a fleetwide brand standard across all onboard media.
- Created a dynamic port information publication. Oversaw the rollout for ports across the world.

#### **EDUCATION**

## CERTIFICATE IN FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON

MARCH TO JUNE 2021 SEATTLE, WA

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS

# BACHELOR OF ARTS, DESIGN PRODUCTION WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY

SEPTEMBER 2000 TO JUNE 2003 SEATTLE, WA

A design program focused on the fundamentals and history of art, design, and color theory. A well-rounded balance of theoretical knowledge and practical skills.